I have a question. The world's strongest
magnet, how strong is it? Your fridge
magnet is probably 0.0001
Tesla. And a one Tesla magnet is
powerful enough to pick up your car. An
MRI machine can get up to about three
Tesla, which is why you don't want to
bring metal anywhere near it. Those
superconducting magnets are so strong
that they align the protons in your
body. That's how they get images like
these. But that is weak compared to this
magnet, which can get up to 45 Tesla.
It's designed to study exotic states of
matter, but that is weak compared to
this magnet. It can only run for a few
milliseconds, but it can hit 100 Tesla.
And the sound that it makes is
terrifying.
But it's still weak compared to the
strongest man-made magnet ever. This
magnet reached 1,200
Tesla. It only worked for a fraction of
a second, but it was so powerful it blew
the doors off the steel chamber. We use
these insanely powerful magnets to do
experiments. To learn more, subscribe.